It's 1975 and they're about to explode.
The Runaways is a music, drama, history film directed by Floria Sigismondi.
Joan Jett and Cherie Currie, two rebellious teenagers from Southern California, become the frontwomen for The
Runaways -- the now-legendary group that paved the way for future generations of female rockers.
Under the Svengali-like influence of impresario Kim
Fowley, the band becomes a huge success.
Joan Jett, played by Kristen Stewart.
Cherie Currie, played by Dakota Fanning.
Kim Fowley, played by Michael Shannon.
Sandy West, played by Stella Maeve.
Lita Ford, played by Scout Taylor-Compton.
Robin, played by Alia Shawkat.
The Runaways is a 2010 American biographical drama film about the 1970s rock band of the same name
written and directed by Floria Sigismondi in her screenwriting and feature directional debut.
It is based on the book Neon Angel: A Memoir of a Runaway
by the band's lead vocalist Cherie Currie.
The film stars Dakota Fanning as Currie, Kristen Stewart as rhythm guitarist and
vocalist Joan Jett, and Michael Shannon as record producer Kim Fowley.
The Runaways depicts the formation of the band in 1975 and focuses on the
relationship between Currie and Jett until Currie's departure from the band.
The film grossed around $4.6 million worldwide and received
generally favorable reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of iron, 1970s, publicity, nightclub, pill.
The tone is emotional.